Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course in this
exercise number 30, we are asked to write a program to check if an array contains a specific value.
So both the video and think about how to check for an array if it contains a specific bad look through
all that, all the elements and search for a specific value.
We have learned in that lecture in the previous videos how to search for a given array for a given value
inside their array, and they see.
And we didn't implement the complete program and like test it in real life.
So in order to write it in a real life program, I will create a function called contains so public
static boolean it's returning Typekit as Boolean and code contains.
This function is called contains.
It took inside its parameter and int array called air air and into the item that we are going to search
for.
OK.
So this method will search inside the air for the specific element item it is contained or not.
OK, so we start for each int and say the array.
This is that for each loop that I have told you inside the lecture that we have specific and a special
type of array of loops that loops it through all the elements of the array.
And for each element inside the array, it will create a variable and end.
And we need to check inside this element if the item that we have passed inside the perimeter is equal
equal to.
And so we are looping through all the elements inside the array and the check.
If the item that we are searching for is equal to and if it is equal to an it return it true because
we our our function is returning Boolean.
OK.
Now it will return false if it is not if it loops through all the elements and exit from this loop without
returning through.
Satisfying the condition that I am equal to, and it will return false, so no elements are found equal
to the item passed.
OK, now let's test this approach.
How to test it, I will create an entire array here.
And array array one equal to that search for let's make our program.
These are the numbers.
OK.
This is the era, and let's search for a system that out that brand.
And I call the math it contains, I will add the method contains called the method contains I will pass
the array one as the first parameter am searching inside their a'wan for what?
For that item, like let's search for the element 14.
OK, let's run and see.
False, it returns false, because Element 14 is not inside these.
This Saturday, now let's search for 21.
OK, if it's here, let's run and see if our algorithm is working fine and here we go, we have true.
So we are checking for the array.
It contains a specific item or not by doing a method called contains and looping through all the elements
of the array and check if this element equal to the last item.
If there's equal, it will return it through and otherwise it would return.